

Kocaeli, Türkiye









linkedin.com/in/kadirtuna20





# **Kadir** Tuna

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Possessing a strong foundation in Electrical-Electronics and Computer Engineering, my academic journey began in Electrical-Electronics Engineering, followed by a transition to a double major in Computer Engineering. As an Erasmus student at Rezekne Technologies Academy in Latvia, I expanded my knowledge of Computer Science, working alongside peers from diverse cultural and academic backgrounds. I hold a certificate from the OSYM YOKDIL Exam (76.25/100) and have completed the B1+ Level Preparation at Pamukkale University, demonstrating proficiency in English. With 3 months of professional experience, I focus on Deep Learning (CNNs, LLMs), Algorithm Design, and back-end development, while continuously improving my skills in Low-Level Languages (C, C++). My long-term goal is to advance as a senior back-end developer, specializing in microservices.

## **EDUCATION**

September 2024 – Present

## Master's in Computer Engineering (30% English)

Gebze Technical University (GTU), Gebze,

Kocaeli, Türkiye

GPA: 3.83/4

September 2018 – December 2023

## Pamukkale University, Denizli, Türkiye

Bachelor's in Computer
 Engineering (Double Major)
 Engineering Faculty,

Cumulative GPA: 3.58/4.00

 Bachelor's in Electrical– Electronics Engineering Engineering Faculty,

Cumulative GPA: 3.21/4.00

English Language Preperation
 B1+ Level

September 2021 – June 2022

## Erasmus+ KA103 Programme in Computer Science

Engineering Faculty, <u>Rezekne Technologies</u>
<u>Academy</u>, Rezekne, Latvia

GPA: 8.47/10

## **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

February 2024 – Present

## Back-End Developer | R&D | Ayasofyazilim (Bilisim Vadisi)

Gebze, Kocaeli

- Developed and maintained back-end services using .NET, EF Core, Microservice Architecture, Layered Architecture, ABP Framework, MongoDB, MSSQL, Redis, Docker, Linux, DDD, OOP, SaaS (Multi-Tenancy), Unit Test, Integration Test, DevOps and GitHub Actions.
- Focused on database modelling and microservice design for scalable applications.

October 2023 – December 2023

## OOP Engineer Intern | IMEYT - R&D | Baykar Technologies

Bahçeşehir, İstanbul

- Designed algorithms and tested performance using C# WPF, Geoprocessing, Python, and Socket Programming.
- Improved software performance through benchmarking and optimization.

July 2023 – September 2023

## Full-Stack Developer Intern | R&D | SAMM Technology

Gebze, Kocaeli

- Developed applications using C# ASP.NET Core, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap5, EF Core, and MSSQL.
- Utilized Docker, Docker Compose, and Docker Swarm for containerization and orchestration.

June 2022 – August 2022

#### Back-End Developer Intern | Software Development | Prizma Software

Pamukkale, Denizli

- Built back-end services using C# ASP.NET Core Web API, Blazor Framework, and EF Core.
- Applied Swagger API, Postman API, JWT Token, and Repository Patterns for API management and security.

## **KEY SKILLS**

- C# .NET Core | ASP.Net Core | WPF | WinForms | ABP | EF Core
- C / C++ Junior to Mid
- Python PyQt | NumPy | Pandas
- Web HTML | CSS | JavaScript | React
- DB MSSQL | PostgreSQL | MongoDB | Redis
- OOP | Design Patterns | Microservices Architecture
- IPC Socket Programming | Message Brokers
- API REST | Postman
- VCS / BMS Git | GitHub | Jira
- Software Testing Unit | Integration
- Docker Compose | Swarm
- Embedded Beginner | PLC Mid
- Sci. Computing MATLAB / Octave Mid
- Geographic Tools GIS | Beginner

#### **HOBBIES**

- Music 4+ years (Guitar, Piano)
- Fitness 3+ years (Swimming, Volleyball)
- Motorcycle Riding
- Chess

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

April 2023

## Fighter UAV Competiton Finalist | Teknofest 2023

Finalist (15<sup>th</sup> place out of 754 teams) as part of Algan UAV team.

November 2022

## Middle Level Python Education | Yazilim

20-hour practical course covering decorators, iterators, database operations, multithreading, etc. in Python.

### **LANGUAGES**

- Turkish NativeSpeaker
- English B2 Level (YOKDIL: 76.25/100)

#### **PROJECTS**

September 2022 - April 2023

## GUI Design and App Integration | Algan UAV Teknofest Team | (Demo)

Denizli, Türkiye

- Developed a GUI to display telemetry data and camera snapshots from the UAV.
- Responsibilities included OOP Design, PyQt5, UI/UX, AI integration, OpenCV, YOLO Model, TCP/UDP Socket Programming, FFMPEG, and Code Integration.

September 2022 – June 2023

## People Counter Server Broadcast | Graduation Thesis | (Code/Live)

Denizli, Türkiye

- Created a Python Flask server that processes video frames to detect and count people using a custom YOLO Object Detection Model.
- Tools used: Python, Numpy, Pandas, Flask, YOLO v3–v7.

April 2020 - June 2020

## Cargo Management WEB API | Recruitment Project | (Code/Live)

Denizli, Türkiye

- Developed a RESTful API for automating cargo order progress and selecting the cheapest carrier.
- Tools used: ASP.NET Web API, MSSQL, Swagger API, EF Core (Code First), Hangfire Cron Jobs, Async Programming, Repository Pattern, 3-Layered Architecture.

September 2018 - Present

More projects available in My Portfolio.

### **ASSOCIATION AND CLUB MEMBERSHIPS**

September 2022 - April 2023

## Volunteer Software Developer | Algan UAV Teknofest Team

Pamukkale University

- Developed orientation, tracking, and locking algorithms for UAVs and designed a GUI.
- Contributed to the team reaching the finals in the "Teknofest 2023 Fighter UAV Competition" held from April 15–19, 2023, in Bursa, Türkiye.
- Utilized tools and technologies including Python, PyQt, OpenCV, TCP/UDP socket programming, multithreading, and the YOLO object detection model.

## **REFERENCES**

**Prof. Dr. Serdar İplikci** Computer Engineering Academician, Pamukkale University

E-mail: iplikci@pau.edu.tr

Assoc. Prof. Meric Cetin Computer Engineering Academician, Pamukkale University

E-mail: mcetin@pau.edu.tr Phone: +90 (258) 296 3208

Ali Bahar Software Engineer, TUBITAK BILGEM

Baran Hasan Bozduman GUI and Testing Developer(IMEYT), Baykar Technologies

Hasan Duraman Embedded Software Testing Engineer, Baykar Technologies

<sup>\*</sup> The phone numbers can be provided upon request